John Kuk

http://john-kuk.com john.kuk@gmail.com, 309-706-2787

John Kuk is an experienced solution architect and manager. His specialties are around systems integration and Service Oriented Architectures. His technical experiences are broad and deep spanning various IBM, Oracle, Microsoft, and Open Source products. He has management experiences collaborating with globally distributed workforces at large organizations. John's contributions over the years highlight his ability to deliver enterprise scale systems and solutions.

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

Skills

Java, C/C++, Javascript, Visual Basic, Windows Batch Scripting, Unix Shell Scripting, COBOL, SQL

Software

Springsource Tool Suite (STS), Spring Framework, Mule ESB, Apache Tomcat, Sun Java Composite Application Platform Suite (Java CAPS), NetBeans, Twitter RECESS, JSHint, Node.js, CSSLint, Twitter Bootstrap, Maven, Subversion, IBM WebSphere Message Broker (WMB), IBM Business Process Management (BPM), IBM WebSphere Integration Developer (WID), IBM WebSphere Process Server (WPS), IBM WebSphere MQ, IBM WebSphere Application Server (WAS), IBM Rational Software Architect (RSA), IBM Rational Application Developer (RAD), IBM WebSphere Business Integration (WBI), IBM InterChange Server (ICS), IBM Rational Team Concert (RTC), IBM Rational Asset Manager (RAM), IBM WebSphere Service Registry and Repository (WSRR), IBM DB2, IBM Visual Age for Java, IBM Visual Age for C, IBM WebSphere Studio Application Developer (WSAD), IBM Clear Quest, IBM Clear Case, IBM Rational Requisite Pro, IBM IMS, BEA WebLogic Integration (WLI), BEA AquaLogic Data Services and Service Bus, Oracle 10g/11g Database, Oracle SQL Developer, Oracle Virtual Directory (OVD), Oracle VirtualBox, Microsoft SQL Server, Microsoft Visual Basic, Microsoft Visual C++, Microsoft Internet Information Services (IIS), Business Objects Enterprise XI, Business Objects Crystal Reports, Siebel

Platform

Windows 7/XP/NT4/2000/2002/2003/2008, Oracle Linux, Red Hat Linux, Ubuntu Linux, AIX Unix, IBM DataPower, OS/390, z/OS

Misc

SOAP Web Services, REST Web Services, Rational Unified Process (RUP), Agile/Scrum, MVC Architecture, Service Oriented Architecture (SOA), Virtualization, Cloud, Aspect Oriented Programming (AOP), XML, XSLT, XSD, DTD, LDAP, Single Sign On, J2EE, Java Messaging Services (JMS), JDBC, ODBC, DAO, UDDI, BPEL, Systems Development Life Cycle (SDLC), Accenture Development Methodologies (ADM)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

State Farm, Web Systems Analyst 3 State Farm Plaza South, Bloomington, IL

11/2011 - Present

- Currently part of the development practices team performing quality reviews to improve design and construction of various parts of the Customer Driven Evolution (CDE) project. While with the team, led two efforts to provide improvements and guidance around web style sheet and Javascript development practices.
- Worked with a small team to evaluate Mule ESB performance as part of the new technical platform introduced to the new technical platform.
- As part of a tactical team evaluated offshore delivered components, and then stepped in to re-factor portions of delivered code to meet standards.

Accenture, Consulting Manager 161 North Clark Street, Chicago, IL

08/2006 - 11/2011

- 08/2011 11/2011, Was the technical delivery lead managing the creation of a new Oracle Web Center Portal for one of the United States largest communications providers. (Town and Country, MO)
- 07/2011 10/2011, Was an enterprise service bus architect that transitioned an IBM Message Broker framework between new team members for the state of North Carolina. (Raleigh, NC)

- 07/2011 10/2011, Conducted review sessions as an integration solution architect to propose improvements for a manufacturing system for one of the largest manufacturers of prescription biopharmaceuticals. (Princeton, NJ)
- 05/2011 07/2011, Web architect involved in estimating, planning, and proposing a Java Open Source web application for one of the world's largest hospitality and management organizations. (White Plains, NY)
- 07/2010 05/2011, Siebel delivery project manager in charge of constructing a new Siebel call center application for the largest nonprofit health provider in the United States. (St Louis, MO)
- 11/2009 06/2010, As part of Accenture's IBM Global Alliance, was acting SOA asset development lead in charge of creating and managing IBM assets to be leveraged by projects worldwide. (Chicago, IL)
- 02/2008 12/2009, Took on several architect roles at one of the top 10 United States health insurers, and built several teams that leveraged IBM technologies in the areas of integration, web, security, data services, and code conversion. (Pittsburgh, PA)
- 12/2007 01/2008, Worked for the world's largest mutual property and casualty company to compose a technical solution to build a comparative auto insurance rating system. (Bloomington, IL)
- 11/2007, Contributed to a SOA proposal for the United States largest health insurer as a technical architect to credential information and skills. (Minneapolis, MN)
- 02/2007 10/2007, Learned Java CAPS and became the integration technical architect in charge of restructuring the world's second largest automotive supply company's integration landscape. (Van Buren Township, MI)
- 10/2006 02/2007, Worked for one of the United States largest power and gas distributors as an integration architect leading framework construction with WLI as part of their transformation program. (San Francisco, CA)
- 09/2006, As part of an internal SOA project, reviewed and contributed to company CBT's that would be used to prepare CIO's with Accenture's perspective on its SOA capabilities. (Chicago, IL)

Country Insurance and Financial Services, Middleware Application Developer 1711 GE Road, Bloomington, IL

05/2000 - 08/2006

- Leveraged WID as part of an effort to integrate Siebel and corporate client data, and built some of the company's first WPS environments.
- Implemented various user interface and application changes to the company's agent portal homepage under the company's WAS platform.
- Led WBI development to integrate data transactions between Siebel and the company's mainframe legacy billing and customer management system.
- As part of a Siebel 7 upgrade project took part in development, technical architecture, and system integration using various IBM integration technologies.
- Was part of the team that converted the company's claims applications into a Siebel 6 application, and leveraged WBI to feed critical insurance policy data into the system.
- Was part of the team to create the company's agent portal which merged a Siebel thin client application with the company's custom WAS portal.
- Was part of the Java development team, coding functionality for a homegrown life insurance illustrations application called Illustrations Anywhere.
- Used Java, XML, and MQ skills to make changes to a document creation application that generated policies for auto, property, and commercial insurance.
- Was part of the company's Customer Web Content project which developed various integration solutions using a variety of IBM development tools.
- Took on-call responsibilities and acted as technical support and a SME for WBI, WAS, Siebel, and various other production systems over the years.

EDUCATION

Illinois State University Normal, IL

12/2000

- Bachelor of Science Applied Computer Science, specializing in Computer Information Systems & Systems Analysis with a minor in Business Administration
- Trained two years in Army Reserve Officers' Training Crops, Military Science, and awarded academic scholarship as well as received a citation and medal for outstanding achievement and exceptional leadership ability

CONTINUING EDUCATION

- IBM WebSphere Message Broker V6.0/6.1 Development Workshop
- Foundations of Sun Java Composite Application Platform Suite
- BEA WebLogic Integration 8.1/8.5
- IBM WebSphere Integration Developer & Process Server
- IBM AIX Korn and bash Shell Programming
- IBM WebSphere Business Integration Server
- IBM MQ Adapter Offering (MQAO)
- Siebel Configuration Using Siebel Tools for 2000, 6.1, 7.0, 7.7
- IBM DB2 Developer Training
- IBM MQ Series Training
- Springsource Spring Foundation Training
- Mulesoft Mule ESB 3 Training

PROFESSIONAL SOCIETIES AND CERTIFICATIONS

 Accenture Master Technology Architect Program, Technology Architect certified as having acquired and demonstrated necessary base skills and experience in the design and delivery of components of technology architecture. Obtained certification May of 2008.

ACTIVITIES AND HOBBIES

• Building Lego models with my 4 year old daughter, watching walking dead with my wife, TaeKwonDo (Black Belt 3rd Degree), running, fishing, snowboarding, welding, video games, Rubix's cube, Google Android, Google App Engine, Open Source Engineering (Arduino), OpenStack, skills based volunteering